How to type in Tamil, Hindi, Bengali, Malayalam, etc. - in MS Word, Facebook, Gmail, etc.?
Simple. With Azhagi+ up and running, start your external application (e.g. MS-Word), press Alt+3 (or Alt+4) in the external application's usual typing area and start transliterating in Tamil. That is all to it. To switch back to type in English, press Alt+3 ( or Alt+4) itself again. As simple as that.

To transliterate in other languages like Hindi, Sanskrit, Telugu, Kannada, Malayalam, etc., you have to press the corresponding hotkey - Ctrl+1, Ctrl+2, Ctrl+3, Ctrl+4, Ctrl+5 and so on. That is all to it. To switch back to type in English, press Ctrl+1, Ctrl+2, etc. itself again. As simple as that. 

To type in other fonts or font encodings or keyboard layouts like SaiIndira, Tamil Bible, Bamini, Tscii, TAM, TAB, Tamil Typewriter, TamilNet99, Inscript, etc. too, you just have to press the corresponding hotkey - Alt+1, Alt+5, Alt+0, Alt+2, Alt+8, Alt+9, Alt+7, Alt+6, Alt+F12 and so on. That is all to it. 

AutoStart with Windows
If you open Azhagi+'s 'Settings' screen and tick certain options, the process of 'starting & using' Azhagi+ will become very easy for you. You can autostart Azhagi+ along with Windows and keep it as a small icon in the system tray, always. To know how to do this, please visit and see http://azhagi.com/oper-plus.html#settings. In this way, if you make Azhagi+ autostart along with Windows, then whenever you wish to type in other languages (or whenever you wish to keep typing alternately in English and other languages), the only thing you have to do is to just press an hotkey like Alt+3. That's all.

Important Note: 
1) If you are unable to type in Tamil, etc. (following the above very simple procedure) OR even otherwise, kindly visit http://azhagi.com/oper-plus.html#step-by-step. 
2) There is inbuilt step-by-step help available too. Just press 'F1' right now OR click the button captioned '? Help' OR click on the 'Help' menu of Azhagi+ and then click the menu item 'How to type in Indian languages?' 
3) If you still need more help, you can always join and post your query in Azhagi's Facebook Group - https://www.facebook.com/groups/Azhagi - which is the online support forum for Azhagi. It is better to read this checklist (http://azhagi.com/helptips.html#checklist) and/or the following help tips, prior to posting your queries.

Tip-1: 
When pressing a hotkey like Alt+3, you should not press '3' from the number pad. You should press the regular '3' which you find at the top row of number keys (below the function keys). i.e. you should press the '3' under the '#' sign. 

Tip-2:
If you are already using an Indic software similar to Azhagi+, then Azhagi+ may not work correctly if some or all of the hotkeys (e.g. Alt+3) of Azhagi+ are already availed by the other Indic software you are using. In such circumstances, to make Azhagi+ work correctly, you may have to follow the instructions here - http://azhagi.com/helptips.html#another

Tip-3:
Please read this - http://azhagi.com/helptips.html#SetRightYourAV

Tip-4:
Caps lock should be always OFF when you type. So, to type L, R, N, etc. (to get letters like ள், ற், ண், etc.), you have to use 'Shift' key and type Shift+L, Shift+R, Shift+N, etc.

Tip-5:
You can change any hotkey (Alt+3, Alt+4, Ctrl+1, etc.) to any other hotkey you prefer. How to set/change hotkey has been explained step-by-step at http://azhagi.com/oper-plus.html#changehotkey.

Tip-6:
If there is no default hotkey already set for your LFK ('Language + Font + Keyboard' combination), then either:
A) You can set a new hotkey for your LFK and use the same to type in your LFK in all the applications. How to set a new hotkey for any LFK has been explained here - http://azhagi.com/oper-plus.html#changehotkey. 
OR
B) You can use the global hotkey (F10) to start typing in your LFK in any application. How to use the global hotkey F10 to type in any LFK has been explained here - http://azhagi.com/oper-plus.html#f10. 

Tip-7:
Azhagi+ helps you type in an alternate Tamil transliteration scheme too - wherein the key mappings are such that  'ee' is mapped to 'ஏ', 'oo' is mapped to 'ஓ', 'w' is mapped to 'ந்', etc. This scheme has been provided to help users who are already accustomed to type using such a scheme. To type using this scheme, you have to press Alt+4 hotkey instead of Alt+3. And, to know the key mappings for this alternate Tamil transliteration scheme, just click on "Tamil (Alt+4 mode)" in the list box adjacent to the button captioned "Key mappings [all languages]". You can view the same key mappings online too at http://azhagi.com/xmls/udph/AzhagiPlus-Tamil-Unicode-UserDefinedPhonetics1.xml 

A few advanced and unique features of Azhagi+:
1) You can easily type in ANY Indian language font [even custom-made] you own, using Azhagi+. For details, please read http://azhagi.com/changecreate.html#create
2) Using a unique feature of Azhagi+, you can transliterate in ANY Tamil font you own. And also,  effect conversion from ANY Tamil font encoding to ANY other Tamil font encoding. It is so simple. For details, please read one or both of http://azhagi.com/anytamilfont-t.html and http://azhagi.com/anytamilfont.html
3) In fact, you can easily create and add ANY 'Language + Font + Keyboard Layout' combination (with your own mappings) to Azhagi+ and start typing using the same. For details, please read http://azhagi.com/changecreate.html#create
4) For any help required related to the above-mentioned unique features or any other aspect of 'Azhagi' free apps, please feel free to write in Azhagi's Facebook Group - https://www.facebook.com/groups/Azhagi - which is the online support forum for Azhagi. The support is also 100% free. 

Love is God. Humility is Power.
Humility is God. Love is Power.

Prayers and Kind Regards
Viswanathan (Author of 'Azhagi' Free Apps)
http://azhagi.com/author.html#GodIsGreat 
http://azhagi.com/aasiriyar.html#GodIsGreat (தமிழில்)
